Their bodies were caged, but not their desires. They
would do anything for a man - or to him.
The Big Doll House is a action, drama film directed by Jack Hill.
Female prisoners in a Philippine jail are being subjected to sadistic torture.
Five of the women -- along with the help of two men -- plot an escape.
Collier, played by Judith Brown.
Grear, played by Pam Grier.
Harrad, played by Brooke Mills.
Alcott, played by Roberta Collins.
Bodine, played by Pat Woodell.
Harry, played by Sid Haig.
The Big Doll House is a 1971 American women-in-prison film starring Pam Grier,
Judy Brown, Roberta Collins, Brooke Mills, and Pat Woodell.
The film follows six female inmates through daily life in
a gritty, unidentified tropical prison.
Later the same year, the film Women in Cages featured a similar story and setting and
much the same cast, and was shot in the same abandoned prison buildings.
A nonsequel follow-up, titled The Big Bird Cage, was released in 1972.
The film explores themes of prison, rape, sadism, exploitation, women's prison.
The tone is emotional.